♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we've got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we'll reset it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko stronger after all ♪
Huh?
Something is not right here.
What do you mean quack?
An alarm signal, and no activated tower?
That’s weird.
And you’re sure about the alarm last night?
Not 100%, I was pretty groggy.
Odd, could you make a little less noise?
No, if I don’t find a DVD of my short film in the next three seconds,
I’ll turn into a pumpkin.
Which short film?
“Natural Granger Two”, or “I Guess Our Guest is a Ghost”?
I Guess Our Guest is a Ghost.
If you want me to become rich and famous,
I absolutely have to give it to TV.
TV? Who’s TV?
His real name is Thomas Vincent
But everybody calls him, TV,
because he’s the famous news reporter on TV.
TV, get it?
TV’s gonna be here in five minutes.
My career is snipped in the bud.
Hey!
Yes, fame, fortune, and glory are mine.
My dear TV, on behalf of the students and faculty,
we’re very honored that you--
Ok, ok, no big deal, time is money.
Uh, this is Edna, my camera, uh, woman, person, whatever.
Never on time, show up late one more time, and you’re finished!
I’ve got a hundred and fifty cameramen
who’d kill for a chance to work with TV.
You. Sweatshirt. Park my car out of sight from the kids, I don’t want them scratching it.
Uh, whoa.
Now, let’s continue with our study of plant life.
After our field trip last week,
I asked you to calculate the yield of field of corn that we visited.
Now who can give me the answer?
Polyakov?
Yeah, one-thousand five-hundred and twenty-seven tonnes.
Really Nicholas?
Well done, you solved the problem of world hunger.
(LAUGHTER)
Quiet down!
Yes?
Give me a panorama shot of the kids.
Ahem, can I help you?
Yes, get out of the shot.
Do our schools still provide a future for our youth?
Faced with the teachers lax attitudes,
we have reason to doubt.
To see how bad it’s become,
all you need to do is pick out a student at random
and ask him his grade-point-average.
You for instance.
99.87 out of 100.
Huh?
Ok, cut,
that’s too high.
Who here has a below 60 average?
Ok son, so you’re flunking out of school, right?
Me? Not exactly. On the other hand,
I have this great DVD to show you.
Oh, this cannot be happening, what’s with this--
(BELL RINGING)
(CHEERING)
I’m so disgusted,
TV didn’t even want to see my masterpiece.
Is that what it means to be a starving artist?
Oh no!
What?
The alarm, Xana’s gone on the attack.
I’ll warn Yumi.
Well I sure hope this goes quickly,
because I don't want to miss meatballs and gravy.
We haven’t had them for ages.
Virtualization!
Watch it, you've got company!
Aelita, stay behind me!
Everyone bring their insecticide?
Yumi!
Supersprint!
Laser arrow!
Thanks, Yumi.
Hey!
Bunch of chickens!
Weird, I guess Xana’s not up to snuff today.
Well, weird or not it’s better for us because we have waiting for us.
Meatballs and gravy!
So hurry up!
Well, my lady, your tower is served.
Aelita, wait!
Look!
The tower is deactivating itself.
Well what do ya know?
What does that mean, Jeremie?
I wish I knew.
Oh no, another tower activated in the Ice Sector.
Again? Unbelievable.
What’s going on?
The tower just deactivated by itself.
I don't get this at all.
Do you think it’s a bug in the supercomputer?
Or a new plot by Xana.
Go to lunch,
I’ll stay here and try to work all this out.
If anything happens,
I’ll give you a shout.
I’ll stay with you, with the two of us, it’ll go faster.
What’s with these little mini-servings,
come on cookie, don’t be shy, load up the meatballs.
Let me tell ya, it sure is no picnic being a field reporter.
Wait, what. Where are all the meatballs?
On TV’s tray.
Oh this is awful.
Any guy who had wheels like this I’d go out with in a heartbeat.
Ok, I’m outta here, I’m starving.
It’s starting up again!
Should I tell the others?
Hang on, it might deactivate by itself again.
Look, it’s snowing!
(CHEERING)
Calm down everyone,
stay in your seats.
The sub-system seems ok too.
Jeremie, the tower is still activated.
Uh oh, bad news.
Maybe this time Xana really is attacking.
That’s enough now,
everyone inside!
Yes, Jeremie?
Xana’s attacking.
(WIND BLOWING)
Inside, on the double!
Come on, I gotcha.
We have to get to Lyoko.
Yeah, you’re right, and I bet the weather is better there.
Jeremie? We’re stuck at school because of the blizzard.
What a nightmare,
Xana’s back to his old self.
Closed, now what?
Follow me.
Cool, the Subsonics.
Here, Mr. TV this’ll keep your hair in place.
(GIGGLING)
Very good, Mrs. Hertz.
You did well to take the children safely to the basement of the science building.
Look Mr Delmas, I found the weather station,
I got this free with my Sumo-Mag-Subscription.
Up there it shows the temperature outside,
uh it’s four degrees below zero.
And down here...
Shows the temperature in here, thirty-seven.
Thirty-seven degrees?
Come on, let’s go down to the boiler room.
Ok everybody.
It’s a scientific fact that if we huddle together we’ll keep warmer.
(SMACK)
Ouch!
It’s a scientific fact that a good slap will keep your cheek warm.
I’m setting it on maximum.
That should warm us up a little.
Edna. stop wasting film.
An unbelievable deep-freeze has taken hold of the city,
and what are you shooting?
Three brats in a basement!
It’s not even PG-13!
People expect spectacular TV from TV.
So let’s get out of this rathole,
and go where the action is , the city!
Not with me.
Oh yeah? Fine.
You’re fired!
(CONFUSION)
Can’t have cold feet on this job.
You can’t go outside,
it’s forty below out there.
My car keys?
Oh.
Um, I-I think I left them in the ignition--
Idiot!
Did you hear that?
Forty below, and there’s no reason for Xana to stop there.
The only solution is to deactivate the tower on Lyoko.
But if we go out, we’ll end up as ice sculptures.
We’ll have to try.
We’ll sneak out of here and search the rooms for warmer gear.
And then we'll run over to the factory.
Ok.
I’m warning you, Herb,
if you fall asleep, I’ll slap you again!
What do you think you;re doing in my car? Get out of here!
Hey, you're not going to leave us in this blizzard, are you?
Fine, I’ll drop you off. Get in the back,
and don't get my soft leather seats dirty, got it?
Stupid power steering.
(LOUD CRASH)
Did you see that?
We’ve gotta go and help them.
Sir?
Yes, Michael?
How c-c-c-cold is it?
F-fifty-eight degrees below zero outside.
Twenty-three degrees in here.
--A deadly cold mishap has hit the city, which buried under ice and snow in a matter of minutes.
The authorities have put the emergency cold weather-- --into action.
But chaos has broken out nonetheless, telephone wires--
I-it wasn’t my fault, it was the p-p-power steering, I--
Yeah right, why don’t you make yourself useful, in the meantime,
and get Sissi and Herb into the boiler room, fast!
Now that’s authority.
Ulrich! Look out!
(SCREAMING)
That was close.
Yumi!
This is why… I like bonsais better...
We’ll get you outta there.
One, two, three.
Forget it, it’s much too heavy.
Go to the factory, that’s more important.
We can’t just leave her here.
She won’t last long in this cold.
Ok, you get to Lyoko,
I’ll stay here with her.
Good luck.
Hang in there, I’m going to go and look for something to get you outta there.
Yes.
We have no choice, Jeremie.
But that’s exactly what Xana’s waiting for, Aelita.
For you to go to Lyoko alone, so he can steal your memory.
If someone doesn’t go and deactivate that tower, Ulrich, Yumi, and Odd will die of cold, and the entire city with them.
Yeah, I guess you're right.,
I’ll launch the virtualization process.
Yumi!
Let. Me Sleep.
No. No, You can sleep later, ok?
Look out, Aelita, hornets on the way!
I can’t see anything for now.
They’re not hornets, they’re flying mantas!
Huh? But they never leave Sector Five.
We have to face facts. Xana is getting more and more powerful.
About face, Aelita, fast!
Well, that’s it.
Think about warm things, Odd.
Tahiti, uh, sauna, heat wave, fireplace.
Flying mines!
Yumi, stay with me.
Ok, no sleeping. Everyone listen up,
I’m gonna tell you a little story.
It’s from when I was a volunteer research subject for the space exploration program.
Aelita, what are you doing? You’re going straight into the Scyphozoa.
(CELESTIAL MUSIC)
Hot springs, blast furnace.
And b-believe it or not, Major Santanos really had Hippopotamus blood in his veins--
(SMACK)
No sleeping!
(SHIVERING)
Aelita, behind you!
Please, hang on. I’m sure Odd’s already on Lyoko.
Magma.
Odd!
Transfer Odd.
Virtualization!
Oh no, more ice.
Leave me.
You won’t get rid of me that easily.
Laser arrow!
Can I drop you off at the next tower, perhaps?
I wouldn’t say no.
Look out behind you!
And so there I--
Another field of flying mines!
Hang on!
Please... Yumi… Don’t give up…
We need you, to fight against Xana...
Odd, the flying mantas are behind us!
Haha, right where I want them.
Here we go.
Yes! There’s an open passage!
Hurry. I’ll cover you.
Shield!
(SCREAMING)
(CELESTIAL HUMMING)
I need you.
(HUMMING CONTINUES)
Tower deactivated.
Yumi?
Yumi!
Oh no! No!
Jeremie, hurry up, launch a return to the past,
Yumi is in trouble!
Ok.
Return to the past, now!
What’s with these mini-servings? Come on, cookie, don’t be shy, load up the meatballs.
Do you really want it?
Oh yeah. What are you, deaf too?
What the--
And if you’re still hungry, there’s seconds.
(LAUGHTER)
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY THE FOXTROT FANATICS